Uzys SMI Merge Tool http://uzys.net
Uzys 통합 자막 생성기 http://uzys.net
www.tvsubtitles.net
판자집 고쳐야 된다고
생각해 본 적 없어?
Do you guys ever think
maybe we should
fix up the shack a little?
괜찮아
It's fine.
- 그걸 왜 고쳐?
- 맞아
Why fix it?
Yeah.
I don't know,
in case we ever bring
모르지, 여자애들이나 뭔가
데려갈 때를 대비해서 말야
girls here or something.
스카티, 너네 엄마나 누나 말고
데려갈 여자가 누가 있냐?
Scotty, what girls
are we gonna bring
besides your mom
or your sister?
됐어, 없던 일로 해
You know what?
Fine. Never mind.
얘들아
Yo, guys.
판자집 문이 열려 있어
The shack door's open.
저거 피야?
Is that blood?
오, 도망가야 돼, 어서!
Oh, man, we should go. Come on!
Is he dead?
죽은 걸까?
He's not moving.
움직이질 않아
피를 많이 흘렸어
That's a lot of blood.
Looks like he got
shot or something.
총에 맞거나 했나봐
Whoa.
워
Smooth move, ex-lax!
살살 움직여, 멍청아!
You guys,
얘들아
money.
돈이야
엄청 많아
And a lot of it.
맙소사,
경찰에 신고해야 돼
Holy crap.
We need to go call the cops.
뭐?
What?
Well, it doesn't look
like he's gonna be making
3:10 투 유마라도 찍었나 봐?
슈퍼 데이브?
that 3:10 to Yuma,
eh, Super Dave?
그는 막차를 탔다고
말씀드릴 수 있을 거 같네요
I'd say he's caught
his last ride.
Name is
텍사스 운전 면허증에 따르면
그의 이름은 로저 매터스네요
Roger Mathers, according
to his Texas driver's license.
가슴에 한 발의
총상이 있고요
Single bullet wound
to the chest.
사입구 주변에 훌륭한
화약 고리가 형성되어 있군
Nice powder ring
around the entry wound.
양말에 묻은 먼지와 돌멩이로
봐선 사막을 하이킹 했나봐
Looks like he was
hiking in the desert,
judging from all the dirt
and burrs in his socks.
네, 뭐, 이 주변엔
그런게 널려 있으니까요
Yeah, well, there's no shortage
of that around here.
No.
그러게
이봐, 니키!
Hey, Nicky!
잠깐만 다녀올게
Hey, uh, give me a second,
will you?
Yeah.
네
이쪽은 CSI 닉 스톡스입니다
This is, uh, CSI Nick Stokes.
콤즈 보안관이시네
지역 법집행관이시지
This is Sheriff Combs.
He's the local law.
Stokes.
How's it going?
스톡스입니다,
안녕하십니까?
보안관께서 희생자를
아신다고 하시더군
Sheriff was telling me
he knew the victim.
But he's from Texas.
How'd you know him?
그는 텍사스 출신인데
어떻게 알고 계셨죠?
지금은 텍사스에
살지 몰라도
Well, he might've been
living in Texas now,
로저 매터스는 바로 여기
but Roger Mathers was
born and raised
엘리스 스프링스에서
나고 자랐습니다
right here in
Ellis Springs.
녀석을 꼬마 때부터
알았거든요
I knew him as a kid.
보안관 말씀으로는
The sheriff
was telling me
희생자가 악명이든 뭐든
유명세를 치뤘다던데
that the victim had
a moment of fame,
or infamy, depending
upon how you look at it.
어떻게 보느냐에
따라 다르겠지만
네, 녀석이 어렸을 때
친구들과 돌아다니다가
Yeah, back when
they were kids,
he and a couple of buddies--
they had the bad luck
재수없게도
무장강도와 마주쳤었죠
to run across an
armed robbery.
그 중에 한 꼬마가
살해당했고요
One of the kids
got killed.
마을이 충격에 빠졌었습니다
Shook up the town pretty bad.
Excuse me, I got to take this.
실례합니다,
급한 전화라서요
네, 브래스입니다
Yeah, go for Brass.
그래서, 보안관님
So, Sheriff,
what do you think
로저가 마을에 돌아와서
뭘 하려 했을 거라 보십니까?
Roger might've been doing
back in town?
And what the hell
was he doing way out here?
무슨 생각으로
돌아온 걸까요?
돈을 추적해 온 녀석이
그가 처음은 아니라서요, 스톡스 씨
Well, he wouldn't be the
first guy to come out here
chasing a payday,
Mr. Stokes.
Loot from the robbery
was never recovered.
도난당했던 돈이
아직 발견되지 않았거든요
수백만 달러의 돈이 어딘 가에서
발견되길 기다리고 있습니다
There's a million-dollar
treasure out here
just waiting to be found.
마을 전설에 따르면 아직
여기 어딘가에 있다고 합디다
Local lore-- they say it's
still out here somewhere.
하
Huh.
무슨 일이에요?
경감님?
What is it, Jim?
딸 아이 일일세
That was about my daughter.
뭐 잘못됐어요?
What's wrong?
녀석이 방금
자살 시도를 했나봐
She, uh, just tried
to kill herself.
♪ CSI 14x22 ♪
Dead in His Tracks
Original Air Date on May 7, 2014
CSI: LV - S14E22 (Season Finale)
Dead in His Tracks
== sync, corrected by elderman ==
@elder_man
출연: 테드 댄슨
D.B. 러셀 役
엘리자베스 슈
쥴리 핀리 役
♪ Who... are you?
조지 이즈
닉 스톡스 役
♪ Who, who, who, who?
조자 폭스
새라 사이들 役
에릭 즈만다
그렉 샌더스 役
♪ Who... are you?
로버트 데이비드 홀
알 로빈스 役
♪ Who, who, who, who?
월레스 랭햄
데이비드 하지스 役
♪ I really wanna know
데이비드 버먼
데이비드 필리스 役
♪ Who... are you?
♪ Oh-oh-oh
♪ Who... ♪
엘리자베스 아느와
모건 브로디 役
♪ Come on, tell me who are you,
you, you ♪
존 웰너
헨리 앤드류스 役
폴 길포일
짐 브래스 役
♪ Are you!
Original Air Date :
May 7, 2014, CBS
약물 과용입니다,
20대 후반 여성이고
We've got an O.D.
Female, late 20s.
자살 시도입니다
Attempted suicide.
클로자핀과 올란자핀을
혼합해 주세요
Cocktail of clozapine,
olanzapine.
Breathing steady,
but shallow.
호흡은 꾸준하지만
약합니다
85/40.
혈압은 85/40이고
Get her into three
and throw up
환자를 3번 방에 옮기고
링거 한 병 더 투입하세요
another bag of ringers, stat.
Yes, Doctor.
- 서둘러 주세요
- 네, 선생님
- 죄송하지만..
- 전 짐 브래스 경감입니다
I'm sorry, sir.
I'm Captain Jim Brass.
경감님,
잠시 기다려 주세요
Captain, I'm gonna
need you to wait.
그녀가 안정되는대로
말씀드리겠습니다
As soon as she's stable,
I'll find you.
방금 들었어요,
정말 유감이에요
We just heard. So sorry.
어떠세요?
How you doing?
I don't know.
모르겠네
지방검사 말로는 엘리가
예심 때문에 여기 있다고 하던데
D.A. said Ellie was here
for a preliminary hearing.
유치장에 있었습니다
She was in a holding cell.
분명 약을 모아놨을 거예요
She's obviously, uh,
stockpiling her meds.
녀석이 자살하고
싶어했을리는 없습니다
I mean, I don't think
she wanted to kill herself.
아이 변호사는 정신 이상에
의한 참작을 탄원 중이거든요
You know, her attorney is,
uh, filing an insanity plea.
아마 그걸 뒷받침할만한
방법에 문제가 생겼던 거 같아요
It might be some screwed-up way
of strengthening their case.
어찌 됐든,
경감님은 여기 계셔야 해요
Whatever's going on,
this is where you need to be.
엘리스 스프링스 사건은
신경쓰지 말게
And don't even think about
the Ellis Springs case.
우리가 맡지,
자넨 여기 일에나 신경 써
We got it covered.
You just take care
of things here.
고맙습니다
Thanks.
이봐, 새라, 사냥꾼의
차에서 보물이라도 나왔어?
Hey, Sara, find anything in
the treasure hunter's car?
건강엔 별로 신경쓰지
않았다는 건 확실해
Well, he wasn't a health
food nut, that's for sure.
Looks like he ran a solar
business down in Plano.
플레이노에서
태양열 사업을 벌였나봐
His name's on the back
as the company owner.
여기 뒷부분에 그의 이름이
사장이라고 적혀 있어
농담하는 거야?
Are you kidding me?
텍사스에서 태양열을 팔아?
Selling solar in Texas?
왜? 텍사스엔 태양이 없어?
What? Texas
doesn't have sun?
텍사스엔 기름이 있잖아
Texas has oil.
내가 어렸을 때
이런 말을 했으면
When I was growing up, you
mention something like this,
it was blasphemy.
신성모독이라 했을 거야
그렇게 생각하는게
편하다면야
Well, these might put
your mind at ease.
주유소 영수증이야
Gasoline receipts.
언제 어디서
기름을 넣었나 보니
Looking at the where
and the whens of his fill-ups,
텍사스에서 곧장 이곳으로
운전해 온 거 같아
I would say
that he drove straight through
from Texas to get here.
왜 그리 서둘렀을까?
Well, why was he
in such a hurry?
모르지
I don't know.
- 그건 뭐야?
- 사진 조각인데
And what is that?
Piece of a photo.
자동차 주변
바닥에서 발견했어
I found it on the ground
near the car.
Can't find
the rest of it.
나머지 부분은 못 찾겠네
Well, it kind of looks
like an aerial photo.
항공 사진의
일부 같아 보이는데
Don't you think?
그런 거 같지?
전설이 진짜일지도 몰라
Maybe the lore is true.
이 지역의 항공사진이면
희생자의 보물지도였겠지
Aerial photo of the area--
could've been
the victim's treasure map.
So, I called on down
to Texas,
텍사스에 전화를 걸어서
희생자의 회사에 있는
사람과 얘기해봤어
and I spoke with someone
at the victim's company.
그가 왜 이리로
달려왔던 건지 말해주던가요?
Did they say why he
came racing up here?
내 생각엔 그가 거기서
재산을 탕진했던 거 같아
You know, my guess is
he was racing away from there.
심각한 재정 문제가
있던 걸로 드러났어
Turns out, he had
serious money troubles.
His company is
그의 회사가 파산했거든
going under.
Got to say,
제가 잃어버린 보물을
발견했다면
if I found a buried
treasure, I'd spend it
망해가는 회사를 살리는 것보다
더 흥미로운 일을 해보겠어요
on something far more exciting
than saving my failing company.
예를 들면?
What do you got in mind?
미친 듯이 여행다니거나
멋진 스포츠카를 타는 거
Like a crazy trip
or a sexy sports car.
- 뭐 그런 거죠
- 아하
Something like that.
Uh-huh.
선배가 가져온 사진 조각엔
확실히 지문이 묻어 있었는데
So, there are
definitely prints
on that piece of photo
you brought in, but
그 중 거의 대부분은
희생자의 것이었어요
pretty much all of them
belong to the victim.
"거의 대부분"이라니?
"Pretty much all of them"?
그의 것이 아닌
부분 지문이 하나 있었는데
Well, there is
one partial print
that's not his, but
it's not enough to run.
검사하기 충분치 않았어요
흥미로운 점은
궁상문 형태라는 거였어요
It's interesting though;
it looks like
a tented arch pattern.
아주 희귀한 거거든요
Which is really rare.
인구 중에 5퍼센트 만이
갖고 있는 거예요
I mean, only, what, five percent
of the population has that.
닉이 지금 희생자의
통화 기록을 보냈어
Well, Nick just got
the phone records of our victim.
그가 텍사스에서 오는 길에
다섯 통의 전화를 했었나봐
He made five calls
on his drive from Texas to here.
전부 타이슨 브릭스에게
건 거였어
All of them to Tyson Briggs.
타이슨 브릭스가 누군데요?
Who's Tyson Briggs?
25년 전 강도와 마주쳤던
다른 두 소년 중 한 명이야
He's one of the other two kids
that got tangled
in the heist 25 years ago.
당신과 로저가
아직 친한가요?
So, were you and
Roger still close?
아직도 대화를 나눕니까?
You guys still talk?
아뇨, 안 그래요
No, not really.
Everything changed
after that day.
그 날 이후로
모든 게 바뀌었거든요
That's why it was so weird,
그래서 걔가 난데없이 전화한게
이상하다고 생각한 이유예요
him calling
out of the blue like that.
뭐라던가요?
What'd he want?
좀 보자고 그러더군요
Wanted to get together.
그래서 만났나요?
And did you?
Yeah.
네, 오랜만에 보니
좋을 거 같았어요
I thought it'd be good
to see him, you know?
만났죠
Get caught up.
근데 로저는 오직
돈 얘기 뿐이더군요
But all Roger could
talk about was money.
He was kind of frantic.
제정신이 아니었어요
심지어 공황상태였어요
Panicked even.
뭔가 깊은 구멍에라도
빠진 거 같았어요
He must've been
in a pretty deep hole.
그가 파묻힌 보물을
찾는다고 말하던가요?
Was he talking about
looking for buried treasure?
그 89년 사건 때
강탈된 돈 말이죠?
You know, the money
from the '89 heist?
그게 녀석이 온 이유였어요
돌아온 이유 말이죠
That was why he was here;
that's why he came back.
That money was gonna be
the answer to all his problems.
그 돈은 자신의 모든 문제에
대한 답일 거라고 했어요
Hmm.
흠
Well, how would he know
where to look for it?
어디서 찾아야 할지
알던가요?
그건 말 안 했어요
Well, he didn't say.
사실대로 말씀 드려서
전 거기 정말 관심 없었어요
And tell you the truth, man,
I really wasn't that interested.
지금은 그 친구를
험담하고 싶지 않네요
Look, man, I'm not trying
to talk bad about the guy now.
그래요, 이해해요,
계속 해보세요
No, that's all right.
I understand. Go ahead.
저와 로저가
함께 했던 내내
The whole time me and Roger
were together,
그는 스카티에 대해
한 번도 언급하지 않았어요
he didn't once mention Scotty.
단지 돈과 보물을 얼마나 간절히
원하는지에 대해서만 얘기했어요
He just kept going on
about the money
and the treasure
and how bad he needed it, man.
녀석은.. 스카티에 대해선
생각조차 해보지도 않았어요
He didn't... man, he didn't
have one single thought
about Scotty.
스카티라면..
그 살해당한 소년 말이죠?
And, Scotty, that's the...
the boy who was killed?
Yeah, we lost
our best friend that day.
네, 저희는 그 날
가장 친한 친구를 잃었어요
아저씨, 제발요,
저흴 쏘지 마세요!
Please, mister,
don't shoot us!
아무한테도 말 안 할게요
We won't tell anyone.
Ben!
벤!
What the hell?
어떻게 된 거야?
What are you guys doing?
너넨 뭐하는 거야?
We just came here to
hang out, mister, I...
저흰 그냥 놀러온 거였어요,
아저씨, 전..
닥쳐!
Shut up!
Hey, bro.
동생아
It's the best
I could do.
난 최선을 다했어
마을로 되돌아갈 순
없었다고
I couldn't go
back to town.
Hey, hey.
이봐, 이봐
벤!
Ben!
안 돼! 젠장!
No! Damn it!
You.
너
Grab the bags.
You're coming with me.
가방을 집어,
나랑 같이 가자
- 저리 가!
- 안 돼요, 안 돼요, 제발!
Get over there!
No. No, please!
가기 싫어요!
I don't want to go!
당장 돈 집어 들어!
Pick up the money now!
You two are gonna stay here.
너희 둘은 여기 있어
Be quiet
or your friend here dies.
조용히 하지 않으면
친구들 죽는다
You get it?
- 알아 들었어?
- 얘들아!
Guys!
Shut up.
Pick up the money!
닥치고 돈 들어!
들라고!
Pick it up!
얘들아! 얘들아!
Guys! Guys!
얘들아! 얘들아! 얘들아!
Guys, help!
얘들아, 도와줘!
We ran as fast as we could
back to town
저희는 보안관
아저씨한테 가려고
최대한 빨리 마을로
달려왔어요
to get the sheriff.
By that time,
it was too late.
그 때는 너무 늦어버렸죠
그 후론 스카티를
보지 못했어요
We never saw Scotty again.
I grew up with
two great friends, man.
전 두 명의 훌륭한 친구와
함께 자랐어요
절대 잊지 못할
친구 말이죠
You know, the kind
you never forget.
이제 둘 다
죽어 버렸네요
Now they're both gone.
친구분 일은 유감입니다
브릭스 씨
Well, I'm sorry for
your loss, Mr. Briggs.
네, 네
Yeah, yeah.
방금 엘리 얘길 들었어요
I just heard about Ellie.
어떻대요?
How is she?
지금 약물 유도 혼수상태야
She's in
an induced coma.
안정됐어, 그러니..
She's stable, so...
경감님은 어떠세요?
How are you holding up?
그 모든 일이
벌어지고 나서
After all that's happened,
내가 여기서 뭘
하는지 조차 모르겠어
I don't even know
what the hell I'm doing here.
마음 한 구석엔 애가 깨어나지
않았으면 하는 바람도 있어
There's a part of me that wishes
she would just not wake up.
I mean,
그게 끔찍한
말이라는 건 알지만..
I know how horrible
that sounds, but, uh...
엘리가 경감님을
여러 번 힘들게 했잖아요
She's put you
through a lot, Jim.
엘리가 법정 심리 때문에
여기 와 있는 거 알지?
You know she's here
for a court hearing, right?
녀석을 법정에서
증언시키려고 했던게
She's gonna
testify in a court
미치고 죽을 지경이었나봐
that I drove her to madness.
To murder.
엘리가 한 짓과
자살하려 했던 건
You are not responsible
for what she did.
Or what she's
done to herself.
경감님 책임이 아니에요
잘 모르겠어
I'm not so sure.
그 살해된 보물
사냥꾼은 어떻게 됐지?
So, what do we got
on our murdered treasure hunter?
지금 작업 중이에요
Well, we are working
on that right now.
방금 89년도 본 사건의
모든 자료들을 가져왔어요
We just pulled all the files
from the original '89 case.
이자들이 당시 용의자들이에요
These were
our suspects involved.
그 동네에 살던 형제죠
A pair of local brothers.
폴과 벤 오말리예요
Paul and Ben O'Malley.
그들은 마피아 중간 보스인
They robbed the house of
마이클 스카노라는
자의 집을 털었었어요
a mid-level Mob boss
named Michael Scarno,
그 과정에서 그들 중
한 명이 총에 맞았고요
and in the process,
one of them was shot.
경찰 보고에 따르면 그들은
According to the police report,
they made off
십만 달러와 귀중품 약간을
가지고 달아났다고 했어요
with close to a hundred grand
and some valuables.
그게 다 인가?
That's all?
닉이 뭔가 큰 보물같은 것에
대해 얘기했었는데
Nick talked like there was
this big treasure involved.
현금과 시계는 공식
절도 보고서의 일부였어요
Well, the cash and
watches are part
of the official
theft report.
하지만 제 기억에
베가스 마피아 사전 저술 당시
But I remember
when I was writing
my Vegas Mob book,
I heard about
이 마이클 스카노란 자에
대해 들은 적이 있어요
this Michael Scarno.
그는 예술품 절도범이었고
He was an art theft guy,
특별한 조각품
일부를 손에 넣었었어요
and he had acquired a
particular piece of sculpture.
페르시아 돌 사자예요
A Persian-stone lion.
와, 저거 2000년도 더 된 거네
Wow, that's over
2,000 years old.
이건 단지 두 개 중
하나일 뿐이에요
And it was just one of a pair.
다른 하나는 최근 영국 경매에서
천만 달러에 달하는 가격에 팔렸죠
The other one just sold
at a British auction
for close to $10 million.
그건 "왜 지금일까"라는 의문에
대한 대답이 될 수 있겠네
Well, that could
explain the "why now" of it all.
희생자가 그 경매에 대한
이야기를 듣고
Could be that our victim
heard about the auction
남아 있는 조각상을
찾으러 온 것일 수도 있어요
and then went looking
for the remaining statue.
어떻게 그 동네 꼬마 세 명을
예전 사건에 끼워맞출 수 있을까?
How do the three local kids
fit into the original story?
Wrong place at the wrong time.
잘못된 시간에
잘못된 장소에 있던 거죠
오말리 형이 그들을 기찻길 옆
판자집에서 발견했어요
The older O'Malley found them
in a railroad shack.
동생은 죽었고요
Brother was dead.
오말리는 어린 소년을 데리고
탈출을 시도했어요
O'Malley then tried
to make a getaway
and took one of
the younger kids with him.
Scotty Gates.
스카티 게이츠요
오말리는 두 시간 이후
후버댐에서 체포됐어요
O'Malley was caught
two hours later
out near Hoover Dam,
but by then,
하지만 그 때 소년과 돈은
사라지고 없었죠
the boy and the
cash were gone.
현재, 보안관은 소년이
미드호 바닥에
Now, the sheriff
has always contended
that the kid ended up at
the bottom of Lake Mead.
빠져 죽었다고
계속 주장하고 있어요
The body was never found?
시신은 발견되지 않았고?
오말리가 소년에게 무슨 짓을
했는지 말하지 않았다던가?
O'Malley didn't say
what he did with the kid?
그럴 기회도 없었어요
He never got a chance to.
다음 날 아침 감옥에서
죽은 채 발견되었거든요
He was found dead in
his jail cell the next morning.
시신도, 돈도,
재판도 없었다라
No body. No money. No trial.
그 밑그림보다는
뭔가 더 있을 거 같은데?
Seems a little bit more
than sketchy, don't you think?
작은 동네의 정의에
대한 거 말이죠?
Case of small-town
justice, maybe?
아니면 작은 동네의
부패일 수도 있어
Or small-town corruption.
어쩌면 지역 경찰이 스카노가
숨겨둔 걸 알았을지도 모르지
Maybe the local cops knew
what kind of stash
Scarno was sitting on.
So this is
what's left of Scotty Gates.
이게 스카티 게이츠의
유품이에요
소년의 모든 존재가
결국 야구 모자와
An entire kid's
existence
comes down to a baseball hat
안경 하나로 요약됐어요
and a pair of glasses.
그의 부모가 어떤 나날을
보내왔을지 상상조차 할 수 없군
Oh, I can't even imagine
what his parents
must've been going through.
Wait a minute.
잠시만요
부분 지문을 찾았어요
Looks like a partial print.
궁상문인 거 같아요
It could be a tented arch.
Sara said
새라 말로는
로저 매터스의 살해 현장에서
she found a tented arch
궁상문을 발견했다고 했어요
at the Roger Mathers
murder scene.
I got your text.
방금 문자 받았어요,
긴급한 일이라면서요
You said it was urgent.
내가 89년도 사건의 증거를
조사하고 있었는데
I was looking through
the evidence from the '89 case,
and I found
a fingerprint.
지문을 하나 발견했어
부분 지문이라
검사하기엔 부족해
It's only a partial--
not enough to run.
그게 궁상문은
아니라고 해줘요
Don't tell me
it has a tented arch.
맞아
It does.
그러면 좌측에 있는 게
오늘 아침 네가 발견한
Okay, so the one
on the left
is from the torn photo that
you guys found this morning,
찢어진 사진에 나온 거고
오른쪽에 있는게
and the one
on the right
25년 전 스카티 게이츠의
안경에 묻어 있는 지문이야
is from Scotty
Gates' glasses,
25 years ago.
그게 정말
같을 수 있어요?
Could they really be the same?
It's a match.
일치해
그 지문은 샘 비숍이란
남자의 것이에요
The fingerprint belongs
to a man named Sam Bishop.
현재 경비원이지만
He is a security
guard now,
89년도엔 엘리스 스프링스에서
콤즈 보안관의 부관으로 있었어요
but back in '89, he was a deputy
in Ellis Springs
under Sheriff Combs.
그리고 이걸 보세요
And get this--
he left the department
그는 스카티 게이츠와
강도 사건이 발생하고 나서
two weeks after the whole thing
with Scotty Gates and the heist.
2주 후 퇴직했어요
Goes a long way to support
our theory of a crooked cop.
비뚤어진 경찰에 대한
우리 이론이 유효하게 됐군
양쪽 살인 현장에 있는
지문이 다 그의 것이에요
We have his fingerprints
at both murder scenes.
어쩌면 범인일 수도 있겠군
Could be our killer, I guess,
과거의 범죄를
덮으려 했던 거지
covering up his crimes
of the past.
뒤쪽으로 가자
Let's take the back.
Can I help you with something?
무슨 일이시죠?
라스베가스 경찰입니다,
누구시죠?
Uh, LVPD. Who are you?
캐런 비숍이요
여기 살아요
Karen Bishop. I live here.
저희는 샘 비숍 씨를
찾고 있습니다
We're looking for
Sam Bishop.
잠깐 이야기 좀
나눌게 있어서요
We'd like to have
a word with him.
Um... yeah.
음.. 네
경찰이 오셨다고
말씀드리죠
I'll let him know you're here.
아뇨, 아뇨,
괜찮습니다
No, no. You know what?
That's fine.
저희가 직접 가겠습니다
고마워요
We'll tell him ourselves.
Thank you.
실례지만,
들어가실 수 없어요
Excuse me,
you can't go in there.
부인
Ma'am.
샘 비숍 씨?
Sam Bishop?
경찰입니다,
잠깐 얘기 좀 하시죠
LVPD. We need to talk.
Let me guess--
about Scotty Gates' murder?
어디 봅시다, 스카티 게이츠
살인 사건 때문에 오신 겁니까?
당신들이 오기를
25년이나 기다려 왔습니다
I've been waiting 25 years
for you to come.
날 체포하는 겁니까?
You boys are arresting me?
장난치지 마시오
You got to be
kidding me.
두 곳의 살인 사건 현장에서
당신의 지문이 나왔습니다, 비숍 씨
We've got your prints at
two murder scenes, Mr. Bishop.
어젯밤엔 로저 매터스,
25년 전엔 스카티 게이츠 말입니다
Roger Mathers' last night and
Scotty Gates' 25 years ago.
도대체 그게
무슨 말인가요?
What the hell
are you talking about?
저희 아버지는 어떤 살인
사건에도 연루되시지 않았어요
My father
wasn't involved
in any murder.
이 집에 대한
수색 영장도 갖고 있습니다
We have a warrant to search
the premises as well.
You have absolutely no idea
what you're doing, do you?
지금 무슨 짓을 벌이고
있는지 모르고 있나 보군요
그를 데리고 나가
Get him out of here.
You're making a huge mistake.
큰 실수하시는 거예요
아버지는 좋은 분이라고요
My father is a good man.
저희가 직접 좀
둘러봐야겠습니다
Well, we'll have a look
around, see for ourselves.
로저 매터스를 살해하는데
사용된 총은 9밀리미터였죠?
The gun that was used
to kill Roger Mathers
was a nine-mil, right?
응, 하지만 그게
여기 숨겨져 있다면
Yeah, but if it's
hidden down here,
만만치 않은 일이 될거야
we got our work
cut out for us.
Am I the only one getting
지금 저만 미친 과학자의
분위기를 느낀 걸까요?
a mad scientist vibe in here?
이 사람이 전직
경찰인줄 알았는데요
Thought this guy
was a former cop.
우, 이것 좀 봐
Ooh, have a
look at this.
89년도 사건 당시
아이들의 모습이에요
These are the boys
from the '89 case.
Old rabbit's foot.
오래된 토끼 발이야
애들이 갖고 있던 거겠지
Like a kid
would have.
살인자가 스카티 게이츠에게서
빼앗은 전리품일 수도 있어요
Could be a trophy the killer
kept from Scotty Gates.
Well, it's got
an evidence tag on it.
증거 태그가 붙어 있어
이건 전부 예전
사건 기록들이에요
And these are all
old case files.
Just who the hell
is this guy?
방금 이 남자가
누구라고 했죠?
부하들께서 제 집에서
살인 무기를 찾지 못한 거 같군요
Assuming your people
didn't find
any murder weapon
in my house.
네, 그렇습니다
비숍 씨
No, they didn't,
Mr. Bishop.
하지만 아주
흥미로운 걸 찾아냈어요
But what they did find
was-was very interesting.
우리와 같은 분이시더군요
You're one of us,
a criminalist.
범죄학자 말이죠
1989년에 엘리스 스프링스
보안관 사무실에 계셨었죠
You were working for Ellis
Springs Sheriff Department
back in 1989.
사실 전 "취미에 빠진 사람"
이라고 불렸었죠
They called me a "hobbyist,"
actually.
뭐, 젊은 부관으로선
막중한 책임감이었을 겁니다
Well, that was
a pretty
heavy responsibility
for a young deputy.
그 분야는 어떻게
배우신 겁니까?
How'd that land
on your back?
스스로 익혔습니다
I volunteered.
과학에 소질이 있었거든요
I had a knack for science.
저희는 어젯밤 발생한
살인 사건을 수사 중인데
We're working an investigation
into a murder that
took place last night.
현장에서 발견한 찢어진 사진에서
당신의 지문이 발견됐어요
Your fingerprint was
on a torn photograph
recovered at the scene.
그걸 설명해주실 수 있나요?
Can you explain that?
전 오래 전 은퇴했습니다
I retired years ago.
Maybe you should
figure that one out.
그건 여러분이
해결해주셔야 될 거 같네요
당신은 은퇴한게 아닙니다
You didn't retire.
해고당한 거죠
You were fired.
1989년 강도 사건 이후
해고당하고 나서는
You were let go right after
the 1989 heist,
여기 당신 파일엔 불복종
때문이라고 적혀있군요
says here in your file,
for insubordination.
불복종은 없었습니다
There was no
insubordination.
전 콤즈 보안관이..
I found evidence
that was, uh...
inconvenient for Sheriff Combs.
불편해할만한
증거를 찾았었습니다
제 증거를 매장할 가장 빠른
방법은 절 매장하는 거였죠
Quickest way
to bury my evidence
was to bury me.
왜 그 증거가 보안관에게
"불편한" 거였나요?
Why was the evidence
"inconvenient" for the sheriff?
가장 너그러운 각본으로요?
Most charitable scenario?
동네 꼬마가 사라졌는데,
죽은 걸로 추정되었고
Local kid was gone,
presumed dead,
두 명의 남자에게
책임을 씌웠어요
along with
the two men responsible.
보안관은 단지 사건을
종결시키고 싶어한 거죠
Sheriff just wanted
the case closed.
그 반대의 각본은요?
Least charitable scenario?
보안관은 부패했어요
Sheriff was dirty.
그 강도짓에 대해 말이죠
In on the heist.
그 말을 뒷받침 할만한
증거가 있을 거 같은데요?
I suppose you have
some evidence to back that up?
벤과 폴 오말리입니다
Ben and Paul O'Malley.
두 형제가 마이클 스카노의
집을 털었었잖아요
Two brothers that ripped off
Michael Scarno's house.
그 당시 마을의
말썽쟁이였었죠
They were local
troublemakers back then.
여섯 번이나
체포됐었습니다
Got arrested half a dozen times.
여러 번, 콤즈 보안관은
녀석들에게
More than once, Sheriff Combs
arranged for them
자신의 집에서
시간제 노역을 시켰습니다
to serve their time
working on his house.
그건 그가 그들을
잘 알고 있었다는 말이군요
So you're saying
that he knew them well.
녀석들에게 강도짓을
시킬 정도로 잘 알았죠
Well enough he could've hired
them to pull off the robbery.
콤즈 보안관이 부패했다는
주장에 대해선 조심하세
Let's be careful
about allegations that
Sheriff Combs is dirty.
그는 30년 넘게
근무해오고 있지 않은가
Guy has over 30 years
under his belt.
네, 만약 그가 예전
강도나 살인에 연루됐었다면
Yeah, well, 30 years
doesn't take away his guilt
30년의 세월이 죄를
씻어주진 않아요
if he was involved in the
original robbery and murder.
하지만 그건 모르잖나
But we don't know that.
이리 와보게
Come here.
자네 말에
동의한다고 쳐보세
Let's say I play along.
콤즈 보안관이 예전
강도 사건에 연루되었고
Let's say Sheriff Combs
was involved
그게 소년의 죽음과
결부시킨다고 쳐보자고
in the original robbery, which
ties him to the kid's death.
왜 25년이 지나고 나서
로저 매터스를 죽인 걸까?
Why would he kill Roger Mathers
25 years after the fact?
우리가 아는 것보다
로저와 소년들이
Maybe Roger and the kids
그 날 더 많이
봤을지도 모르죠
saw more that day
than we realized.
지금, 로저가 돌아왔고
돈을 간절히 원했잖아요
Now, Roger has come back,
he's desperate for money.
어쩌면 그의 다음 행동은
Maybe his next move
보안관을 협박하는
것일 수도 있었을테고요
is to try
to blackmail the sheriff.
세 문장에 두 번의
"어쩌면"이 들어갔네
That's two "maybe""
in three sentences.
그게 그에게
동기를 준 거예요
It does give him motive.
이봐, 난 그의 편이 아냐
Look, I'm not
in the man's corner.
단지 조심스럽게
진행하자고 하는 거야
I'm just saying,
proceed with caution.
이 샘 비숍이란 남자 말야
This guy, Sam Bishop--
그가 수행했던 과학 수사를
조사하고 있는데
I'm looking at
the forensics he was doing.
말도 안 돼
It's crazy.
정말, 시대를 앞서 나갔어
I mean,
he was way, way
ahead of his time.
다형 단백질 분석과
발사잔여물 분석
Polymorphic protein analysis,
analyzing gunshot residue.
아미노산 오염을
자신만의 공식으로 분석했어
He has his own formulas here
for amino acid stains.
와우
Wow.
이 항공 사진들을
비숍의 상자에서 발견했는데
I found all of these
aerial photos in Bishop's box.
이건 희생자의 자동차 옆에서
발견한 조각과 많이 비슷해보여
They look a lot like the piece
you found by
the victim's car,
하지만 완벽히
일치하는 게 없네
but, I mean, there's not one
that's a perfect match.
그 찢어진 조각의
원본 사진이 없거나
There's not one with
a... with a tear on it
or anything like
that, which means
로저 매터스가 원본을
가지고 있었다는 거야
Roger Mathers had the only copy.
그만이 보물 지도를
갖고 있었던 거지
He had the only treasure map.
왜 샘 비숍의 지문이
있었는지 설명되네
Explains why Sam Bishop's
fingerprint was on it.
그의 사진 중
하나였던 거야
It was one of his photos.
의문점은, 어떻게
로저 매터스가 갖게 되었냐?야
Question is:
how did Roger Mathers get it?
샘, 이것들은
당신의 사진들입니다
Sam, these were your photos.
우리가 로저 매터스의
자동차 주변에서 발견한
That's why your fingerprint's
on the fragment that we found
조각에 당신의
지문이 묻은 이유죠
near Roger Mathers' car.
그에게 이 사진을
건네준 겁니까?
Did you give him
this photograph?
아뇨, 그가 어떻게
구했는지는 알 수 없습니다
No. And I have no idea
how he got it.
이건 전부 예전
사건 사진들이에요
These are all
original case photos.
25년 동안 같은
증거 상자에 들어 있었죠
Been sitting in the same
evidence box for 25 years.
실은 아주 인상적이에요
They're very
impressive, actually.
이건 요즘 드론으로 하는
지도 제작 방법이거든요
It's the kind of mapping
we do with drones nowadays.
그 때는 드론을
쓰지 않으셨죠?
But you didn't have a
drone back then, did you?
네
No.
대신 이걸 썼습니다
But I had this.
I mounted a camera
from a suspension rig
기상 관측 풍선 밑에
서스펜션 장치를 걸어서
카메라를 설치했죠
slung beneath
a weather balloon.
카메라의
셀프 타이머를 수정해서
The camera's self-timer
was modified
자동적으로 사진을
찍을 수 있게 했어요
to fire off an entire roll
of film, automatically.
일주일에 걸쳐
그 지역의 지도를 얻었죠
Took about a week
to map the region.
스카티 게이츠의 시신을
수색하는 더 나은 방법이 없었어요
There was no better way to
search for Scotty Gates' body.
네, 이제 여기까지
하셔야 될 거 같군요, 샘
Yeah, I'm-I'm gonna
stop you right there, Sam.
제가 마이클 스카노의
변호인과 대화해봤는데
See, I had a conversation
with Michael Scarno's attorney.
Discovered an
interesting connection
당신과 옛 범죄 보스의
흥미로운 연결점이 발견됐거든요
between you and
the old crime boss.
그가 당신에게 돈을 주고
이 사진들을 샀더군요, 샘
He paid you
for those photos, Sam,
그리고 그건 당신이 콤즈
보안관에 의해 해고된 직후였고요
and that was
after you got fired
by Sheriff Combs.
Hold on a minute.
잠깐만요
당신은 소년의
시신을 찾은게 아니에요
You weren't looking
for the kid's body.
스카노가 자신의 잃어버린
돈을 찾기 위해 당신을 고용한 거죠
Scarno hired you
to find his missing loot,
- 그의 보물 말이죠
- 아뇨, 반장님은 이해 못합니다
his treasure.
No, you don't understand...
스카노가 준 돈에 대해
계속 부정하시렵니까?
Are you going to deny
that you were
on Scarno's payroll?
아뇨, 인정해요
No, I'm not.
그래요, 제가
늙은이의 돈을 받았어요
Yes, I took the old man's money.
막 해고당한 상태였고,
어린 딸을 키우고 있었어요
I'd just been fired,
I had a little girl to raise.
하지만 전 어떤 사라진 돈이나
보물 따위엔 관심 없었어요
But I never
gave a damn
about any missing loot,
any treasure.
그건 스카티를
찾을 수 있는 기회였다고요
It was a chance to find Scotty.
샘, 우린 어젯밤 로저 매터스가
갖고 있었던 사진이 필요합니다
Sam, we need the photo
that Roger Mathers
had last night.
원본은 어디 있죠?
Where are the negatives?
There it is.
저기 있네요
어젯밤 로저 매터스가 살해
당했을 때 갖고 있던 사진이에요
The photograph that
Roger Mathers was carrying
the night he was murdered.
그 엄청 특별한게 뭐였길래
그가 살해당한 걸까?
what's so damn special about it
that got him killed?
샘 비숍이 이 사진들을 찍었을 땐
분명 대충 훑어보기만 했을 거야
Sam Bishop must have
scoured these photos
back when he took them.
아무 것도 보지 못했어
He didn't
see anything.
네, 하지만 그는 1989년의
기술로 작업한 거잖아요
Yeah, but he was working
with 1989 technology.
Whoa.
워
잠깐만
Hold it.
저거 보여?
Do you see that?
땅바닥에
불규칙한 형태가 있어
There's an irregular
pattern in the ground.
최근에 뒤집혀진
흙 같아 보여요
Looks like the dirt
had been recently turned over.
이걸 최근의 위성 사진과
비교해 볼 수 있겠어요
I can run this
against a current
satellite photo,
GPS 좌표 좀 줘보세요
get the GPS
coordinates.
가까워지고 있어요
Well, we got to be close.
우리가 입력한 좌표
바로 위로 다가가고 있네요
Coordinates we have
put us just about
on top of it.
응, 거의 다 온 거 같아
Yeah. I think we're there.
This is recent.
최근에 생긴 거 같은데요
맞네요,
이 구멍은 신선해요
Yeah. This hole
looks fresh.
여기 흙에 생긴
자국 좀 보세요
Look at the impression
in the dirt here.
사자 조각상
때문일 수도 있어요
Could be from the lion statue.
누군가 우릴
보물에게로 안내했어
Someone beat us to the treasure.
Greg.
그렉
테니스화 같은데
Looks like a tennis shoe.
아주 오래된 거 같아
Or it was, a long time ago.
뼈예요
That's a bone.
여기 묻혀있던 건
보물 뿐만이 아니었어
Wasn't just the treasure
that's buried here.
No.
네
이건 스카티 게이츠의
무덤이에요
This is Scotty Gates' grave.
이건 굴착을 시작하기 전에
구멍에서 본을 뜬 건데
Here's the cast
I pulled from the hole
before they
started digging.
확실히 사자 조각상과
일치해 보여요
Sure looks like a match
for the lion statue to me.
그래, 삽도 발견됐어
Yeah, we found
a shovel, too.
지금껏 이곳에 스카티 게이츠와
조각상이 묻혀 있었던 거야
So Scotty Gates
and the statue
were buried right here
all this time.
난 그 이야기에서 소년이 미드호
바닥에 잠긴 채 죽은 걸로 알았는데
I thought the story was that
the kid ended up
on the bottom of Lake Mead.
그건 콤즈 보안관이
항상 말하던 거였잖아요
Well, that's what
Sheriff Combs has always said.
그 반면, 샘 비숍의
이론도 들었잖아요
Then again, I mean,
you heard Sam Bishop's theory.
보안관이 강도에
연루되었다는 거요
The sheriff was in on the heist.
호랑이도 제 말하면
온다더니 말이죠
Speak of the devil.
당신들이 무덤을 발견했다는
무전을 듣고 왔습니다
So I have to hear
through radio traffic
that you discovered
a grave.
아직 수색 초기 단계예요
We're still in
the early stages.
당신이 파낸 유해가
스카티 게이츠라면
If the remains you're digging up
there are Scotty Gates,
제가 아직 그 사건의
주요 수사관입니다
I am still the lead detective
on that case.
보안관 님,
지금 당장 이곳에선
Sheriff, right now, this is
part of our investigation
저희가 로저 매터스의
살인 사건을 수사 중입니다
into the murder of
Roger Mathers.
당신이 다른 증거를
못 찾았다는 건
And you found
no other evidence
이게 내 사건의 일부라는 걸
뜻하는 거 아닙니까?
that would indicate
this is part of my case?
백만 달러짜리 조각상
말씀하시는 건가요?
You mean like
a million-dollar statue?
여기 있는 모든 건
저희 연구실로 가져갈 겁니다
Everything here
is going back to our lab.
뭔가 찾으면 알려드리죠
We'll let you know what we find.
All these years, he was
just a half-mile from town.
이 모든 세월 동안
녀석은 마을에서 겨우
800미터 밖에 있었어요
I should have found him.
제가 찾았어야 했는데
스카티의 부모는 아들이
실종돼서 비탄에 빠졌었죠
Scotty's parents were devastated
by his disappearance.
Whole town was.
마을 전체도 그랬고요
그의 어머니는..
But his mother--
it just pushed her
over the edge.
벼랑 끝으로 내몰렸어요
일주일 그리고
한 달 동안
For weeks and months,
마을 곳곳에
아들의 사진을 붙였어요
she posted his picture
all over town.
She never stopped
looking for him,
아들을 찾는 걸
멈추지 않았죠
비록, 마음 속에는 아들이
죽었다는 걸 알았던 거 같지만요
even though, in her heart,
I think she knew he was dead.
무슨 일이 벌어졌는지 알지도
못한 채 슬퍼하기는 힘드니까요
Hard to grieve without knowing
what happened.
제가 그녀에게 스카티를
찾아주겠다고 약속했었어요
I promised her
I'd find Scotty.
Did everything I could,
but in the end...
모든 걸 시도했지만
결국은..
I let her down.
그녀를 실망시켰어요
Sam, I want to apologize to you
샘, 제가 종전에 예단했던 것에
대해 사과드리고 싶군요
for the assumptions
I made earlier.
Gentlemen.
- 여러분
- 박사님
Doc.
법치의학자와 얘기해봤네
I spoke with
the forensic odontologist.
치과 기록은 시신이
스카티 게이츠의 것이
Dental records
confirm the remains
are definitely those
of Scotty Gates.
확실하다고 확인되었어
네, 고맙습니다
Okay, thanks.
그 밖에 알려주실 건요?
Anything else
you can tell us?
확실히, 내 관찰은
상당한 부패로 인해 제한되네
Well, obviously, my observations
are limited by
the advanced decomposition.
사인도 알아낼 수 없고요?
Cause of death out
of the question?
꼭 그렇진 않아
Not necessarily.
여기에 있는
골절과 자국에 주목했어
I noticed some
fracturing here
and an indentation.
처음엔, 이게 25년 동안 시신이
묻혀서 생긴 결과로 생각했네
First, I thought
it was the result
of the body being buried
for 25 years.
But on closer look,
하지만 자세히 살펴보니
충격에 의한 압착이 보였어
there seems to be
some impact compression.
Someone struck him in the head.
누군가 그의
머리를 때린 거군요
Or he fell and hit his head;
it's hard to say which.
아니면 넘어지면서 머리를
부딪혔을 수도 있어요
- 확실히 말하긴 어렵습니다
- 제가 좀 봐도 될까요?
Do you mind?
No.
그러게
So this jagged mark here,
that's the line of impact?
들쭉날쭉한 자국이 있어요
이것도 충격에 의한 건가요?
Yeah.
그렇네, 내가 말했던 압착을
볼 수 있을 걸세
You can see the
compression I mentioned.
What do you think?
무슨 생각하세요?
조각상의
기초 부분과 일치해요
It matches the base
of the statue.
그렇군요
Mm-hmm.
스카티는 돌 사자에
맞아 죽은 거예요
Scotty was killed
with the stone lion.
Whoever buried that
was not hiding treasure.
누가 그걸 묻었든
보물을 숨기려던 게 아니에요
살인 무기를
버리려던 거였어요
They were ditching
their murder weapon.
엘리
Ellie.
우리가 어쩌다
이렇게 된 거냐?
How did we get here, huh?
어떻게 이런 데까지
오게 된 걸까?
How did we get here
to this place?
Was it because, uh, I
wasn't your real father?
내가 네 친 아빠가
아니었기 때문이니?
I mean, we never
told you--
그게 별 일 아니라고
생각했기 때문에
we didn't think
it was a big deal.
너한테 절대
말하지 않은 거란다
하지만 어쩌면 네가
본능적으로 알았고
But maybe you
instinctively knew
날 원망하게 됐을지도
모르겠구나
and you held
it against me.
그런 거니?
Is that it?
그런..
Is...
아빠와 딸 사이에
자연적인 연결같은..
I mean, the natural connection
between a father and daughter,
유대감,
우리에겐 그런게 없었지
the bond-- we never had that.
우리가 서로 사랑하지
않았기 때문일까?
Was it because
we didn't love each other?
난.. 널 사랑한 줄 알았어
I mean,
I thought I loved you.
네가 곤경에 처할 때마다
I mean, every time
you were in trouble,
난 거기 있었어
I was there.
네게 왔지
I came.
널 구하고
도우려고 했어
Tried to save you, help you.
그게 사랑이 아니라면..
I mean, if that's not love...
나도 모르겠다,
사랑이란 게 뭔지
I-I don't know
what love is, then.
하지만 넌 날 계속
밀어내고 또 밀어냈지
But you kept pushing me away
and pushing me away.
그리고 이제
여기 함께 있어
And now we're here.
이런 식으로
계속 할 순 없다, 엘리
I can't go on like this, Ellie.
I think
I've discovered a secret
내가 지금 역사상
가장 아름다운 여성에 대한
about the most beautiful
woman in history.
비밀을 발견한 거 같아
Kate Upton?
케이트 업튼요?
역사에서 말야, 헨리
In history, Henry.
클레오파트라에
대한 얘기야
I was talking about Cleopatra.
Oh. Fascinating,
but I am busy.
오, 매혹적이죠
하지만 전 바빠요
그렉과 새라 선배가 구멍에서
발견한 삽에서 나온 DNA를
I just came to tell you
that I had no luck
분리시키지 못했다는
말을 하려고 온 거예요
isolating DNA
from the shovel
Greg and Sara
found by the hole.
Something in the sample
네가 추출하던 중 표본에 있는
뭔가가 망가졌단 얘기지?
screwed up your extraction,
didn't it? Mm-hmm.
네
Just as Cleopatra
and I expected.
내가 기대했던
클레오파트라처럼 말야
좋아요, 들어볼게요
Fine, I'll bite.
망가진 표본과 클레오파트라가
무슨 관련이 있는 거죠?
What does my screwed-up sample
have to do with Cleopatra?
사해에서 나온 무기물이지
Minerals from
the Dead Sea.
그 중 13퍼센트는 이 세상의
어느 물에서도 나오지 않는 거야
13 of them-- not found in water
anywhere else in the world.
언제나처럼,
이해가 안 되네요
As usual, I'm not
following you.
There was lotion
on the shovel handle.
삽 손잡이에
로션이 묻어 있었어
그 표본은 마그네슘, 브롬화물,
역청, 칼슘 그리고 칼륨이
The sample contained
a particular proportion
of magnesium, bromide,
bitumen, calcium and potassium.
특정한 비율로
함유되어 있어
추출 실패의 설명이 되는
고농도의 염분 함량이네요
The high salt content
would explain why
my extraction failed.
오직 한 군데의
공급자 만이
Only one vendor sells a version
with the precise
내가 찾아낸
정밀한 비율의 무기물을
mineral proportions
that I've identified,
오직 인터넷으로만 판매해
and they only
offer it online.
I'm waiting
바로 지금 이 지역 고객들의
명단을 기다리는 중이야
for a list of
local customers as we speak.
오늘 아침 삽
하나를 발견했어요
We found a shovel this morning,
사막에서 말이죠
out in the desert.
손잡이에 로션이 묻어 있었어요
아주 특별한 로션요
It had lotion on the handle,
a very specific lotion.
지금 말하고 있는
그 로션 알고 있죠? 캐런?
You know the stuff I'm talking
about, don't you, Karen?
네?
Huh?
당신이 거기 있었어요
You were out there.
보물을 꺼내려고 스카티 게이츠의
무덤을 판 거 같은데요
I think you went out there
and dug up Scotty Gates' grave
to get to that treasure.
잠깐만요,
"스카티의 무덤"이라뇨?
Wait, what do you mean,
"Scotty's grave"?
We were just looking
for the statue.
우리는 단지 조각상을
찾고 있었을 뿐이었어요
우리요?
We?
Who'd you go out there with,
Karen?
누구랑 같이
갔던 거죠? 캐런?
- 로저요
- 로저?
Roger.
Roger?
Roger Mathers?
로저 매터스요?
How'd you end up out
in the desert with him?
그와 사막에서
어떻게 헤어지셨죠?
이틀 전 아버지의 작업장을
침입한 로저를 잡았었어요
I caught Roger
breaking into
my father's workshop
two nights ago.
어떤 사진을 손에 넣기 위해
발버둥치더라고요
He was desperate to get
his hands on some photographs.
아버지의
항공 사진 말이군요
Your dad's aerial photos.
Well, why didn't you
just call the cops?
근데 왜 바로 경찰에
신고하지 않았나요?
그럴려고 했는데
I was about to,
but then Roger started
로저가 보물에 대한
이야기를 하기 시작했어요
talking about the treasure.
The stone lion,
you know?
돌 사자 아시죠?
그게 전설일 뿐만 아니라
정말 귀한 물건이라더군요
He said it wasn't just lore,
that it was really
worth something.
아버지의 사진이 있으면
찾을 수 있다고 생각한 거죠
He thought that with my dad's
photos, he could find it.
And he offered to cut you
in on the deal.
그는 당신을 끼워주는
조건으로 거래를 제안했군요
그래서 그를 돕기로
한 거고요, 그렇죠?
That's why you
decided to help him, hmm?
I figured, why not?
안 될게 뭐 있어?
라고 생각했어요
If anybody deserves
a piece of that treasure,
그 보물을 받을 자격이 있는
사람이 누구냐라고 한다면
저와 아버지일 거예요
it's me and my father.
That case
ruined our lives.
그 사건이
우리 삶을 망가뜨렸어요
그래서 둘이
무덤을 파러 갔군요?
So the two of you went out
there to dig it up, huh?
그게 계획이었어요
That was the plan.
하지만 실패했죠
But it didn't happen.
We were able to find the spot,
항공사진을 이용해서
그 장소를 찾는데는 성공했지만요
pretty much,
using the aerial photo.
It's got to be close.
거의 다 왔어
사진에 나와 있는
파이프 같이 생겼어
These look like the pipes
that are in the picture.
No. No, no.
아니, 아냐, 아냐
No!
안 돼!
누군가 우리를 앞질렀어요
Somebody beat us to it.
I need the money.
난 돈이 필요해
맙소사,
그 조각상이 필요하다고!
God, I need the statue!
- 이봐..
- 됐어!
Hey...
No!
날 내버려 둬
Just get away from me.
Go!
가라고!
그길로 떠났어요
I walked away.
그게 그를 본
마지막이었어요
That was the last time
I saw him--
무릎을 꿇고, 울더라고요
on his knees, crying.
I've known Roger
since we were kids.
어렸을 때부터
로저를 알아 왔어요
I would never hurt him.
그를 절대
해칠 수 없다고요
캐런과 얘기했다는 걸
알려주려고 오신 건가요?
Come here to tell me
you talked to Karen?
따님이 당신의 예전 사건 기록을
빼돌린 사람 중 한 명이더군요, 샘
Your daughter was the one who
raided your old case files, Sam.
She gave the aerial photos
to Roger Mathers.
로저 매터스에게
항공사진도 줬고요
I can't say
I'm surprised.
놀랐다고 말씀드릴 순
없겠네요
Her whole life,
she had to put up with
그 아이는 평생 사건에 대한
제 집착을 참아왔거든요
my obsession
with the case.
그럴 자격을 가질만하다고
느꼈다는 게 이해가 돼요
Makes sense she'd feel entitled.
결국, 그녀와 로저는 사막으로
무덤을 파러 나갔어요
Evidentially, she and Roger
went out to the desert
and they were digging around.
아무 것도
찾지 못했지만요
They didn't find anything.
But looks like you did.
근데 당신은 찾은 거 같군요
진짜 돌 사자는
거의 2000년 묵었죠
The real stone lion is
almost 2,000 years old.
이건 아직 완성도 못했고요
This one isn't
even finished yet.
시멘트네요?
Cement?
Exact size and weight
as the original.
진본과 크기와 무게가 같죠
살인 무기의
완벽한 복제품이에요
It's a perfect copy
of the murder weapon.
이리 와 보시죠,
뭔가 보여드릴게요
Come here, I want to show you
something. Look at this.
이건 소년의 해골과
같은 크기의 모형입니다
This is a mock-up of the boy's
skull, complete with injuries.
다친 부위도 재현했고요
그래서 당신의 계획은 뭡니까?
So what's your plan?
전 스카티를 죽였을 때의
타격을 반복해서
Well, I am going
to re-enact the murder,
당시 살인 사건을 재현하고
살인자와 콤즈 보안관이
try and duplicate the blow
that killed Scotty,
prove it's consistent
with a killer
같은 체구와 골격이라는 걸
증명하려는 겁니다
the same size and frame
as Sheriff Combs.
You really think he did it?
정말 그가
그랬다고 생각하나요?
Well, that's what
I want to find out.
그게 바로 제가
알아내려고 하는 거죠
나쁜 생각은 아니네요
Not a bad idea.
그게 좋은 생각이라고 말하는
반장님의 방식인가요?
Is that your way of telling me
it's a good idea?
네, 네, 그렇습니다
Yeah. Yeah, it is.
괜찮으시다면 제 팀원들과
함께 힘을 합쳐서
I do think my
guys could, uh,
offer a few improvements,
몇 가지 발전된 기술을
이용하는 게 어떨런지요
if you don't mind
joining forces.
이건 선생님의
모형과 비슷하지만
So this is
just like yours,
only we took it
a little bit further.
저희가 조금 더
발전시켰습니다
Just a little bit.
아주 조금 말이죠
Well, it's for practical reasons
more than anything else.
뭐, 무엇보다 실용적인
이유 때문일 뿐이에요
당신이 직접 실험을 했다면
If you were to do
the experiment,
아마 모형 해골을 열 개도
더 부숴뜨려야 했을 거예요
you'd probably have to destroy
about a dozen skulls.
But our head here
하지만 저희 해골은 무수한
타격을 견딜 수 있고
can sustain
numerous blows,
외상의 결과를 컴퓨터로
표시해줄 수 있어요
and the resulting trauma will be
simulated by that computer.
And I assume that,
제 생각엔 우리가 외상의
범위를 알고 있기 때문에
since we know
the extent of the trauma,
타격 당시의
정확한 각도와
you can set a target zone
힘에 대한 목표 지점을
설정할 수 있을 거 같군요
for the exact force
and angle of the impact.
네, 그리고 컴퓨터는
스카티 게이츠를 죽인 타격을
Yes. And that computer
will let us know
when we perfectly
recreate the blow
완벽히 재현해서
알려줄 겁니다
that killed Scotty Gates.
Very cool.
아주 멋지군요
What are we waiting for?
그럼 시작해 볼까요?
부상 위치가 보안관의 키와
체구와는 일치하지 않는군요
The injuries
just aren't consistent
with the sheriff's
height and build.
보안관이 스카티를
죽였을 가능성은 없어요
There's no way the sheriff
could've killed Scotty.
결과에 따르면
범인은 더 작고
Well, according to this,
the killer was smaller,
거의 150cm 정도 키에
왼손잡이에요
barely five-feet tall
and left-handed.
제가 부관이었을 때 유소년
야구 코치를 했던 적이 있습니다
Back when I was a deputy, I used
to coach some youth baseball.
There was this one kid,
투수를 맡았던
한 소년이 있었는데
a pitcher,
왼손잡이였어요
a mean southpaw.
Mr. Briggs?
브릭스 씨?
또 다른 대화를
해야 할 거 같군요
Think we need to
have another talk.
제가 알고 있는 로저에 대한
얘기를 다 해드렸는데요
I already told you everything
I know about Roger.
네, 이제 스카티 게이츠에 대해
알고 있는 모든 걸 말씀해주시죠
Yeah, but now you're
gonna tell me everything
you know about
Scotty Gates.
그건 25년 전에 저지른
살인에서부터 시작되겠죠?
That's where the killing
all started 25 years ago.
제발요, 아저씨,
저흴 쏘지 마세요
Please, mister, don't shoot us.
아무 것도 말 안 할게요
We won't tell anyone.
죽은 거 같아
I think he's dead.
That's what you said before.
방금 전에도
그렇게 말했잖아
가방을 들어
Come on, grab the bags.
잠깐, 잠깐, 잠깐, 잠깐!
Wait, wait, wait, wait!
너네 뭐하는 거야?
What are you doing?
We-we can't.
이러면 안 돼
He's dead.
저 사람 죽었잖아
돈은 소용 없을 거라고
He's not gonna use it.
그래, 우리한테도 마찬가지야
경찰에 신고해야 돼
Yeah, but it's not ours.
We have to call the police.
아무에게도
신고하지 않을 거야
We're not
calling anybody.
이제, 입 닥치고
가방이나 들어!
Now, shut up and
grab the bags!
싫어
No.
안 돼, 이건 바보 짓이야,
이럴 수 없어!
No, this is stupid. We can't!
Don't be a baby!
애들 같이 굴지마!
여긴 우리 아지트야,
뭐가 있든 우리 꺼라고
This is our hideout, and
whatever's in it is ours.
Now, shut up...
그러니 입 다물고
가방이나 들어
...and grab the bags.
바보야, 내 안경을
부숴뜨릴 것까진 없었잖아
Idiot, you didn't have
to break my glasses.
아빠가 날 죽일 거라고!
My dad's gonna kill me!
이제 새 안경을 살 수 있어
Here, now you can
buy new glasses.
그만 해, 로저
이건 우리 돈이 아냐
Quit it, Roger.
It's not our money.
경찰이 우리가 갖게
놔두지 않을 거라고
The cops aren't
gonna let us keep it.
경찰에 말하지 않을 거야,
멍청아
We're not telling
the cops, stupid.
아무한테도
말 안 할 거라고
We're not telling anybody.
내가 말했지
I told you.
- 신고해야 돼
- 맙소사, 스카티
We have to.
God, Scotty,
쪼다 같이 굴지마!
stop being such a wuss!
쪼다 같이 구는 게 아냐
똑똑하게 구는 거라고
I'm not being a wuss.
I'm being smart.
평범하게.. 말야
I'm being... normal.
There's a dead guy back there.
죽은 사람이 저기 있어
난 집에 가서
경찰에 신고할 거야!
I'm going home,
and I'm calling the cops!
스카티, 내가 경고했지
Scotty, I'm warning you.
엿이나 먹어
Screw you.
넌 내 두목이 아냐!
You're not the
boss of me!
그를 해치려던 건
아니었어요
I didn't mean to hurt him.
I just...
전 그냥..
그냥..
I just...
갑자기 폭발했어요
I just snapped.
Yeah, just those...
those bags of cash--
네, 단지 그 돈 가방이..
it just seemed like
all the money in the world.
세상에 있는 돈의
전부인 것처럼 느껴졌거든요
I just didn't want
nobody to take it.
아무도 그걸 갖게
하고 싶지 않았어요
그래서 최고의
친구를 죽인 거군요
So you killed your best friend.
아뇨, 제가
죽이지 않았어요
No. I didn't kill him.
I mean,
전..
I hit him.
그냥 때리기만 했어요
걔는 죽지 않았어요
But he wasn't dead.
이봐요, 타이슨
Oh, come on, Tyson.
그의 해골이 부서졌어요
He had a fractured skull.
나랑 놀 생각 하지 말아요
Stop playing
these games with me.
거기서 무슨 일이
있었는지 말해봐요
Tell me what happened out there.
누군가..
누군가가 나타났어요
Somebody... somebody else
was out there that day.
저희가 추적당하는지도
몰랐어요
We didn't know
we'd been followed.
얘들아!
Hey, guys!
You guys better
shut him up.
얘 조용히 시켜야 돼
Someone's coming.
누군가 오고 있어
젠장, 캐런, 왜 항상
우릴 따라다니는 거야?
Damn it, Karen. Why do you
always have to follow us?
Didn't you hear what I said?
내 말 못 들었어?
There's a car coming.
차가 오고 있다고
쉿
Shh.
젠장!
Damn it!
안 돼!
No!
So, you smothered him?
그래서, 당신이
그를 질식시켰나요?
Look, I felt bad.
이봐요, 저도 후회해요
But in the moment,
it was him or all of us.
하지만 그 순간엔,
걔와 우리 중 선택해야 했어요
그래서, 당신들 셋이서
So, the three of
you buried Scotty
그 조각상과 함께
스카티를 묻은 건가요?
out in the desert
along with that statue?
누군가 그를
찾아낼까봐 걱정됐어요
We were worried
someone would find him.
하지만 곧바로,
촛점이 미드호로 옮겨졌고
But right away,
the focus shifted to Lake Mead,
그래서 아무도 못 찾았죠
so no one ever did.
그 모든 돈은 어떻게 됐죠?
현금 말이죠
What happened to all
that money? The cash?
로저의 집 현관
아래 숨겨놨어요
We hid it under the porch
at Roger's house.
몇 달 후, 그의 할머니가
담배를 들고 의자에서 주무시다가
Couple of months later,
his grandmother fell asleep
on the couch
with a cigarette in her hand.
집이 완전히
불 타버렸어요
Burned the house to the ground.
So, Scotty died
for nothing.
그럼, 스카티는
헛되이 죽은 거군요
저흰 그냥 애들이었어요
We were just kids.
멍청한 애들요
Stupid kids.
네, 근데 당신은 더 이상
어린애가 아니에요, 캐런
Yeah, well, you're not
a kid anymore, Karen.
Know what you are?
당신이 뭔지 알아요?
거짓말쟁이에요
You're a liar.
I think you lied to us the
last time you came in here.
지난 번에 당신이 여기 왔을 때
거짓말 했던 거 같은데요
당신과 로저가 전 날 밤에
둘이서 돌 사자를 찾았다고요
Think that you and Roger
found that stone lion
the other night, the two of you.
You know what
else I think?
제가 무슨
생각하는지 알아요?
I think when you got
to the cars...
차로 돌아가던 중에..
일이 틀어졌던 거 같아요
...something went wrong.
That wasn't the deal, Roger.
You said we'd split it 50/50.
그건 거래 조건이 아니었어, 로저
반반으로 나눈다고 했었잖아
나눈다고는 했지만
어떻게라고는 말 안 했어
I said we'd split it;
I didn't say how.
넌 내가 그 조각상이 가치 있다고
말해주기 전까진 알지도 못했잖아
You didn't even know
the statue was
worth anything until I told you.
아버지 사진이 없었으면
찾지도 못했을 거면서
And you never
would've found it
without my
father's photos.
I'll cut you in
for a finder's fee.
중개 수수료는 떼어줄게
Come on, Karen.
왜 그래, 캐런
What are you gonna do?
어쩌려고?
날 죽일 거야?
You gonna kill me?
스카티를 죽였던 것처럼?
Like you killed Scotty?
Not a bad theory.
나쁜 이론은 아니네요
문제는, 어떤 증거도
없다는 거예요
Problem is,
you don't have any evidence.
아버지께서 항상 가르치셨죠,
증거가 없으면 사건도 없다
My father always taught me:
no evidence, no case.
There is no way
그녀가 스카티 게이츠를
죽인 걸 증명할만한
that we can get her
for Scotty Gates' murder.
어떠한 방법도 없어요
그녀는 당시 11살이었고
She was 11 at the time,
사인조차
결론지을 수 없잖아요
and we can't even conclude
a cause of death.
그녀가 로저 매터스를
죽였다는 걸 증명해야 해
We have to get her for
killing Roger Mathers.
I know, but we don't
have the evidence.
알아요, 하지만
증거가 없어요
그리고 우리가 찾아낼 때쯤엔
자취를 감춰버릴 거예요
And by the time we do,
she will have
covered her tracks.
Sam? You
looking for me?
샘? 절 찾아오신 건가요?
캐런이 십대일 때
When Karen was a teenager,
she used to go down to
the creek bed behind our house.
집 뒤에 있는
개울가에 가서 놀곤 했죠
거기에 있는 조그만 비밀 장소에
담배를 숨겨 두곤 했어요
She had this little hiding place
down there where she'd
stash her cigarettes,
thinking I-I didn't know.
제가 모르는 줄
알았나봐요
어젯밤에 거길 가 봤어요
I took a look
down there tonight.
이게 제가 생각하는
바로 그거라면
If this is what
I think it is,
your daughter can go
to prison for a long time.
따님은 오랫동안
감옥에 가야만 할 겁니다
9밀리미터예요
Nine millimeter.
로저 매터스를 죽인 것과
같은 구경이에요
Same caliber
that killed Roger Mathers.
All for this.
모든 게 이것 때문이군요
몇 년 동안, 그게 실제로
존재하는 건지 궁금했어요
You know,
for years, I wondered
if that thing really existed.
Now, more than ever,
I wish it hadn't.
이제는, 더욱 더 그게
없었으면 하는 생각이네요
I thought I knew my little girl.
전 제 딸을
잘 안다고 생각했어요
우리 사이에
비밀도 없다고 생각했고요
I thought we had no secrets.
25년 동안, 그 아이는
진실을 숨기고 있었어요
For 25 years, she'd been
hiding the truth from me.
I don't understand it.
이해가 안 돼요
전 단지..
I just...
유감입니다, 진심이에요
I'm sorry. I really am.
자식을 위해
모든 걸 다하잖아요
You do everything
you can for your kid.
You-you give them everything.
모든 걸 주고요
모든 걸요
Everything.
마음을 아프게 하는
힘까지 말이죠
Including the power
to break your heart.
경감님, 소식이 있으면
듣고 싶다고 하셨죠
Captain, you wanted
to know if there was news.
네
Yeah.
엘리의 뇌에 생긴
부기가 가라앉아서
The swelling in Ellie's brain
has subsided enough
that we've reduced
the medication.
투약량을 줄였습니다
이제 대답할 수 있어요
She is responsive now.
- 깨어났습니까?
- 네
She's awake?
Yes.
하지만 여전히
회복 중이에요
But still in recovery.
알겠습니다
고맙습니다, 선생님
I understand.
Thank you, Doctor.
여기서 계속
서성이셨다고 하더라고요
They told me you were hovering.
그래
Yeah.
난 그냥..
확인하고 싶어서..
I just want to, uh, make
sure that you were...
괜찮은지요?
All right?
우리 둘 다 그렇기는
힘들다는 거 알고 있잖아요
We both know that
that's not really possible.
왜 온 거예요?
Why'd you even come?
I guess I'm...
나는..
널 포기할 준비가..
just not ready to...
아직 안 됐던 거 같다, 엘리
give up on you, Ellie.
이건 아빠 잘못이 아니에요
This is not your fault.
항상 잘못은
제게 있었잖아요
There's always been
something wrong with me.
- 그건 사실이 아냐
- 절 그냥 보내주셔야 해요
You should just let me go.
I've tried.
난 노력했다
Believe me.
믿어다오
근데 그럴 순 없어
But I can't.
I mean...
그게..
you're all I have left.
넌 내게 남은 전부야
봐라, 네가..
Look, I'm going to, uh...
쉬게 내버려 둘게
잠들 수 있게 말야, 알겠지?
I'm gonna let you rest,
let you sleep, okay?
아뇨, 가지 마세요
No. Stay.
제발요, 아빠
Please, Dad?
안녕하세요, 경감님
Hey, Jim.
Hmm.
흠
D.B. 어서 들어와 앉게
D.B., come in. Sit down.
I hear Ellie's
out of the woods.
엘리가 고비를
넘겼다는 소식을 들었어요
그렇네
Yeah.
Two of you able to talk?
대화 좀 나누셨어요?
응, 그랬지
Yeah, we did.
잠깐 동안
For a while.
괜찮으세요?
You all right?
뭐, 괜찮아
I am, actually.
술 한 잔 줄까?
Can I buy you a drink?
좋죠
Yeah.
Here you go.
여깄네
- 건배
Happy days.
Happy day.
You're a little calmer
than I thought you might be.
제가 생각했던 것보다는
좀 더 차분하시군요
You sure you're all right?
괜찮은 거 확실해요?
그래, 방금 내 딸과
네 시간 동안의 대화를 나눴어
Yeah, I just had
a four-hour conversation
with my daughter.
그건 지난 15년 간
내게 없었던 일이야
That's something that hasn't
happened to me in 15 years.
우리에게 서로가
필요하다는 걸 깨달았어
We realize
that we need each other.
지금보다 더 말야
Even more now.
제가 경감님이라면 좀 더..
I-I would be a little...
little bit cautious
if I were you.
신중할 거 같아요
"Cautious"?
What do you mean?
"신중하다"?
그게 무슨 말인가?
자네 생각엔 엘리가 날
속이기라도 한다는 건가?
You think she's trying
to manipulate me-- is that it?
난 그 아이를 사랑해, D.B.
I love her, D.B.
걜 믿어야만 하고
I have to trust her.
She's all I got.
그 아인 내 전부야
그 아이 곁에 있고 싶으면
정말 있어줄 거야
And I want to be there for her,
I mean, really be there.
도와줄 거고,
여느 아빠들처럼 말이지
Help her out,
the way any father would.
잘 됐군요
Good for you.
And I hope it works out.
I really do.
그리고 잘 풀리길 바랍니다
정말로요
Well, you and me both.
우리 둘 다 잘 돼야지
운이 좀 따라준다면야,
누가 알겠어?
And with a little luck,
who knows?
Okay.
그래요
I think I'm gonna
hit the road.
전 이제 퇴근해
봐야 될 거 같군요
Okay.
그러게
Yeah.
네
같이 나가시겠어요?
Want to walk out with me?
No, I think I'm gonna
hang out here for a while.
아니, 난 조금만
더 있다 가겠네
생각할게 좀 있어서 말야
I got to figure some things out.
Okay.
그러세요
== sync, corrected by elderman ==
@elder_man
CSI LV Season 14를
시청해주셔서 감사드립니다
번역: 북극곰